conrad.com 2019-04-11

# None

## **Your personal data and how we protect them**

**What is personal data?**  
Personal data is information that can be assigned to your person. This includes, for example, your name, your address, your telephone number and your e-mail address.

**How does CONRAD protect your personal data?**  
At conrad.com and in the mobile applications, your personal data is encrypted during the ordering process and within your customer account using SSL (Secure Socket Layer, key exchange: RSA 1024 bit, encryption of user data: Triple-DES 1024 Bit) over the Internet. Within the mobile applications, the contents of the order process are analyzed by so-called parsing and displayed in the application. Credit card data is collected, processed and stored in encrypted form exclusively by our payment service provider Ingenico Payment Services. You can recognize a secure connection by the fact that the address displayed in the browser starts with "https://..." instead of "http://..." and a padlock appears at the bottom right-hand edge of the window. We protect our website and other systems by technical and organizational measures against loss, destruction, access, modification or distribution of your data by unauthorized persons.

**When and why do we use your data?**  
When does CONRAD use and process personal data? We know that the careful handling of your personal data is very important to you. Since CONRAD attaches great importance to data protection, we strictly adhere to the legal provisions of the Federal Data Protection Act and the Telemedia Act when collecting, processing and using data. In principle, you can use our website and our mobile applications without leaving any personal data behind. The personal data and information you provide us with is used by CONRAD to process orders, deliver goods and process payments. The delivery of the article ordered by you is carried out by a transport company commissioned by us. To this end, we will send your e-mail address to this carrier so that the carrier can provide you with information on the status of your shipments and a specific delivery date by e-mail. If you no longer wish to receive this service, you can object to the transmission of your e-mail address at any time. Your objection should be sent to sales@conrad.com. Furthermore we need your data to inform you about orders, products, services and offers of CONRAD. We only use e-mail advertising to the extent permitted by law or if you have specifically authorized us to do so. If you register for our newsletter, we use the data required for this or separately communicated by you in order to send you our e-mail newsletter on a regular basis. When using the Q&A service of our technical customer service, your personal data will be passed on and processed by the IT service provider Bazaarvoice. The company provides technical and administrative support from our technical specialists so that we can answer your questions as quickly as possible. The services around the topic product evaluations (reviews & ratings) are also supported by the company Bazaarvoice. The Bazaarvoices Privacy Policy can be found at <http://www.bazaarvoice.com/de/privacy-policy/>   
We collect, store and process your data for the entire processing of your purchase, including any subsequent guarantees, for our service, technical administration and our own marketing purposes. Your personal data will be deleted if there are no legal storage obligations to the contrary and if you have asserted a claim for deletion, if the data is no longer required to fulfil the purpose for which it was stored or if its storage is inadmissible for other legal reasons. If your account information is merged via an automatic or duplicate check initiated by you, you agree that information from the old account (payment experience, orders, etc.) is transferred to the new account. When using the Conrad customer card, the purchases made are transferred within the Conrad Group.

**Advantage offers of Sovendus GmbH:**  
For the selection of an advantage offer that is of regional interest to you, we will pseudonymise and encrypt the form of address, year of birth, country, postcode, hash value of the e-mail address and your IP address to Sovendus GmbH, Moltkestr. 11, 76133 Karlsruhe (Sovendus) (Art. 6 Para.1 f DSGVO). The pseudonymised hash value of the e-mail address is also used to take account of a possible objection to advertising by Sovendus (Art. 21 para. 3, Art. 6 para. 1 c DSGVO). The IP address is used by Sovendus exclusively for data security purposes and as a rule anonymised after seven days (Art. 6 Para.1 f DSGVO). When you click on a special offer, Sovendus will also receive your name, your address data and your e-mail address in encrypted form in preparation for the personalised request for the special offer from the product provider (Art. 6 Para.1 b, f DSGVO). For more information about Sovendus processing your data, please see our online privacy policy at [www.sovendus.de/datenschutz](https://www.conrad.com/ce/en/www.sovendus.de/datenschutz).

**What does CONRAD do with personal data?**  
Your personal data are stored in our EDP primarily for optimal order processing and customer care.  
Inventory data, such as previous purchase orders and payment experiences, are included in the selection of possible payment methods made available to you. If we make advance payments, e.g. in the case of a purchase on account, we may obtain credit information from Bürgel Wirtschaftsinformationen GmbH & Co. KG, Gasstr. 18, 22761 Hamburg, and/or Schufa Holding AG, Kormoranweg 5, 65201 Wiesbaden. For this purpose, we transmit the personal data required for a credit assessment to Bürgel Wirtschaftsinformationen GmbH & Co. KG, Gasstr. 18, 22761 Hamburg, and/or Schufa Holding AG, Kormoranweg 5, 65201 Wiesbaden, Germany, and use the information received about the statistical probability of non-payment for a considered decision on the establishment, implementation or termination of the contractual relationship.   
The credit information can contain probability values (score values), which are calculated on the basis of scientifically recognised mathematical-statistical procedures and in the calculation of which address data, among other things, are included. Your concerns worthy of protection will be taken into account in accordance with the statutory provisions.   
For the purpose of deciding on the establishment, execution or termination of the contractual relationship, we collect or use probability values that include transaction data and microgeographically aggregated information in their calculation.   
We save the contract text and send you the order data by e-mail. You can view the GTC at any time. You can view your past orders in our customer login area.

**Customer account**  
For each customer who registers accordingly, we set up password-protected direct access to his stored inventory data (customer account). Here you can view data about your completed, open and recently sent orders and manage your address data, bank details and the newsletter. You undertake to treat the personal access data confidentially and not to make them accessible to any unauthorised third parties. We cannot accept liability for misused passwords, unless we are responsible for the misuse. Once you have finished communicating with us, you should close the browser window or mobile applications, especially if you share your computer or mobile devices with others.

**Courses with Conrad**  
Personal data are only collected and processed in this context if you use the course offers and the personal data are required for processing your inquiry, your order or for creating anonymous statistical evaluations. All data not marked as mandatory are voluntary. By entering and sending the data you give us your consent to the automated processing or use of the data. In some cases it may be necessary for us to pass on some of your personal data to third parties, for example to cooperation partners or to the organiser of the event. Also in these cases your data will be used exclusively for the provision of our services and will be destroyed within the legal deadlines. Under no circumstances will your data be passed on, sold or used for commercial purposes to uninvolved third parties.

**How do we use cookies and similar technologies?**  
Does CONRAD use cookies?  
A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer when you surf the Conrad site. A cookie can only contain information that we ourselves send to your computer - private data cannot be read out with it. If you accept the cookies on our site, we do not have access to your personal information, but we can identify your computer using the cookies. Like many webshops, we use cookies to personalize the internet shop and the mobile applications for you and so that you can fill up and manage your shopping basket during your session with orders.   
Most of the cookies we use are deleted from your hard disk at the end of the browser session (so-called session cookies).   
Other cookies remain on your computer and enable us to recognize your computer on your next visit (so-called permanent cookies). These cookies make it unnecessary for you to re-enter your e-mail address for subsequent orders.   
If you do not want to take advantage of cookies, you can modify the cookie handling in the security settings of your browser. Usually the setting option can be found in the Tools menu under Settings or Internet Options. However, we will then no longer be able to offer you some of the functionalities of our Internet shop and mobile applications. To use our shopping cart, temporary cookies must be enabled.

**Third party cookies**  
Conrad uses advertising on other websites via advertising partners or advertising networks. These advertising partners use so-called third party cookies, which are activated by conrad.com after their visit, but can only be read out by the respective advertising partner. These third party cookies are used to measure the success of advertising measures used between the advertising partner and us. Our partner companies are not permitted to collect, process or use personal data via our website using cookies. Only the call of the conrad.com side and an advertising measure switched by the advertising partner is seized.

**Log files**  
Whenever CONRAD pages are accessed, usage data is transmitted through the respective Internet browser and stored in log files, the so-called server log files. The data records stored in this way contain the following data: Date and time of access, name of the page accessed, IP address, referrer URL (originating URL from which you accessed the website), the amount of data transferred, as well as product and version information of the browser used.

**Use of Google reCaptcha**  
To protect our online services we use so-called CAPTCHAs to decide whether the other party is a human being or a machine. This is done to determine whether entries were made via people or machines that are often misused. Because this query is retrieved from a Google server, Google will create a cookie for the duration of the query. For more information about Google Captcha's privacy policy, click here

**Google (Universal) Analytics**  
This website and mobile applications use Google (Universal) Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. "("Google"). Google (Universal) Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is activated on this website, Google will reduce your IP address within Member States of the European Union or in other countries party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area beforehand. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide the website operator with other services relating to website and Internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser within the framework of Google (Universal) Analytics is not merged with other Google data. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser add-on available under the following [Google Analytics deactivate]() link.   
Alternatively to the browser add-on or if you visit our pages via a mobile device, please click the following Google (Universal) Analytics opt-out link to prevent future collection by Google (Universal) Analytics within this website (the opt-out only works in the browser and only for this domain). An opt-out cookie is stored on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this . [Google Analytics deactivate]() link again.   
We use Google (Universal) Analytics including the functions of Universal Analytics. Universal Analytics allows us to analyze the activities on our pages across devices (e.g. for access via laptop and later via a tablet). This is made possible by the pseudonymous assignment of a user ID to a user. Such an assignment occurs, for example, when you register for a customer account or log into your customer account. For non-registered users we use an anonymous ID. However, no personal data will be forwarded to Google. Even if Universal Analytics adds additional functions to Google (Universal) Analytics, this does not mean that it restricts data protection measures such as IP masking or the browser add-on. We will only perform session additions on registered and unregistered sessions of users if our users have not withdrawn their consent to such session additions through the browser add-on or by clicking on the Google (Universal) Analytics opt-out link, or if such merging is permitted under applicable laws and regulations. 

Our website uses Optimize 360 (<https://www.google.com/analytics/optimize/>) to determine statistical parameters for the use of our offers. Anonymous measured values are collected. The tests use cookies to recognize computer systems whose runtime is limited to the duration of the test. IP addresses are not stored in the procedure. 

For reasons of transparency, we would like to point out that we use the Google Tag Manager. This manager does not collect any personal data. The Tag Manager makes it easier for us to integrate and manage our tags. Tags are small code elements used, among other things, to measure traffic and visitor behavior, to measure the impact of online advertising and social channels, to set up remarketing and targeting, and to test and optimize websites. For more information about the Google Tag Manager, see <https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html>. 

We also deliver our contributions as Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) via Analytics. It is therefore possible that after a Google search with your smartphone, for example, you may read our contributions on the Internet and they are not even on our servers. Instead, it may be that the pages are delivered directly from the cache of third-party providers such as Google. You can recognize this by the fact that the URL from which you accessed this page does not contain our domain name (i.e. our website) but e.g. the domain name of Google. Google will not change the source code of our site. 

If the AMP version of the site is stored in the cache of Google or other third parties and accessed from there, we have no influence on data processing and the handling of your IP address. We take care that we do not collect any personal data via our AMP pages. For this reason, the IP address - from our site - is transmitted exclusively anonymously.

**Hotjar**  
To improve usability and customer experience we use the Hotjar analysis service of Hotjar Ltd, a European company based in Malta (Hotjar Ltd, Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, Europe). This function enables the anonymous recording of mouse and scroll movements, mouse clicks and keyboard entries. Hotjar uses a tracking code to collect and transfer your data. When you visit a website that uses Hotjar, the tracking code automatically collects the data based on your activity and stores you on the Hotjar servers (in Ireland). In addition, the cookies placed on your computer or terminal by the website also collect data. Furthermore, Hotjar enables us to obtain anonymous user feedback. The possibility of session recording offered by Hotjar will not be used by us under any circumstances. Additional information on functions and data usage using Hotjar can be found at: [https://www.hotjar.com/privacy.](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy)

**FeedDynamics**  
In order to design and optimize this website and our marketing activities in line with requirements, anonymized data is collected and stored using solutions and technologies from econda GmbH and user profiles are created from this data using pseudonyms. For this purpose, cookies may be used that enable the recognition of an Internet browser. However, user profiles are not merged with data about the bearer of the pseudonym without the express consent of the visitor. In particular, IP addresses are made unrecognizable immediately after receipt, which makes it impossible to assign user profiles to IP addresses. The analysis of user behaviour is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the anonymised analysis of user behaviour in order to optimise both his website and his advertising activities. Visitors to this website can object to this data collection and storage at any time for the future here: <https://www.econda.de/widerruf-zur-datenspeicherung/>

The objection only applies to the device and the web browser on which it was set. Please repeat the process on all devices if necessary. If you delete the opt-out cookie, requests are sent to econda again.

**Xplosion / emetriq**  
This website may use technologies of emetriq GmbH, Vorsetzen 35, 20459 Hamburg, Germany, to collect and store anonymized data for marketing and optimization purposes. emetriq does everything to maintain the anonymity of the data made available, i.e. emetriq does not store any IP addresses or personal data. emetriq collects information about the surfing behavior of Internet users unknown to emetriq, e.g. which pages or products were viewed in the shops of our cooperation partners. emetriq assigns the stored information to an anonymous, multi-digit identification number which is stored in a cookie on the user's computer and which under no circumstances allows any inference to the user's person. In addition, the data is bundled to at least 30 users. This excludes individual assignment. Even by combining the stored information, emetriq is not able to identify a person. You have the option of deactivating emetriq's behavior-based online advertising (opt-out). An opt-out at emetriq does not prevent the display of such advertisements in general.

**Ve Interactive**  
We use the services of Ve Interactive DACH GmbH (Französische Straße 47, 10117 Berlin, hereinafter "Ve"). In providing its services, Ve collects personal data from users who visit our websites. For this purpose Ve uses cookies and other similar technologies. Detailed information about the technologies Ve uses is available in Ve's [cookie policy](https://www.ve.com/de/cookies-richtlinie). A listing of the purposes for which Ve collects personal data is listed in Ve's [privacy policy](https://www.ve.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung). In general, through the use of cookies, Ve collects personal data from users, especially contact information and behavioral data. Ve uses this personal information to draw conclusions about the user's personal preferences and to personalize the user's web experience, for example by displaying personalized offers when visiting customer websites or similarly personalizing the customer's website to the user and displaying personalized advertisements when visiting customer websites or websites of third parties. Ve and we are jointly responsible for the collection of personal data according to Art. 26 GDPR. Details can be found in Ve's [privacy policy](https://www.ve.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung). End users can prevent the processing of their personal data by Ve by various means. The available options for preventing data processing are contained in Ve's [privacy policy](https://www.ve.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung) among others operating the opt-out button under <https://www.ve.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung#opting-out> or using the opt-out mechanism of IAB Europe at [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out-interface.](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out-interface)

**Criteo**  
This website also uses the Criteo-Service service of Criteo SA, Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France. This service is used to provide targeted advertising to users who have already visited our website and are interested in what we have to offer on this website and on websites that also use the Criteo-Service service. This advertising is displayed on the basis of information about the visit to the respective Internet pages, which are stored on the user's computer in cookies, among other things. These text files are read out for specific product recommendations during subsequent visits to the website. For this purpose, a randomly generated identification number is stored in the cookies. Neither this number nor the information about your visits to the Internet pages can be assigned to you personally. Under no circumstances will this data be used to personally identify you as a visitor to our website. You can prevent the storage and use of information by Criteo's service by exercising your right to opt-out. If you make use of this right, a new cookie (opt-out cookie) is set in your browser. This cookie signals to Criteo's service that Criteo may no longer collect and process data about your usage behavior. If all cookies in your browser are deleted, the opt-out cookie is also affected.

**Yahoo**  
This website uses Yahoo Gemini, a marketing service provider operated by Oath (EMEA) Limited 5-7 Point Square, North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland. Yahoo Gemini supports the delivery of personalized and behavior-based advertising material via the Internet. User information is collected and stored in anonymous form and it is not possible to identify a natural person by using Yahoo Gemini. Yahoo Gemini uses cookies for this purpose, which can be deactivated at any time.

**Microsoft / Bing**  
On our pages we use the Conversion Tracking of Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA. Microsoft Bing Ads will place a cookie on your computer if you access our website via a Microsoft Bing ad. Microsoft Bing and we can see in this way that someone has clicked on an ad, has been redirected to our website and has reached a previously defined target page (conversion page). We only see the total number of users who clicked on a Bing ad and were then redirected to the conversion page. No personal information about the identity of the user will be disclosed.   
If you do not want information about your behavior to be used by Microsoft as described above, you can refuse the setting of a cookie required for this purpose - for example, using a browser setting that generally deactivates the automatic setting of cookies. You can also prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website and the processing of this data by Microsoft by opting out. Further information on data protection and the cookies used at Microsoft and Bing Ads can be found on the Microsoft website at <https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement>

**TradeDoubler**  
We are participants in the partner programs of TradeDoubler GmbH, Herzog-Wilhelm-Straße 26, 80331 Munich. This is an advertising service. TradeDoubler uses a cookie on the visitor's computer to correctly record sales and/or leads. TradeDoubler cookies do not store any personal data, but only the ID of the referring partner and the order number of the advertising material (banner, text link or similar) clicked on by the page visitor. When a transaction is concluded, the Partner ID is used to assign the commission to be paid to the referring partner. Further information is available at: <http://www.tradedoubler.com/de/privacy-policy/>

**Retailer web**  
This website also uses the service retailerweb GmbH & Co. KG, Kaiserstrasse 23, 90403 Nuremberg, Germany. With the help of this service, users who have already visited and visited our website once will be able to have been interested in our offers, on this website and on websites that also use the service retailerweb-Service, targeted advertisements are offered. This advertising is displayed on the basis of information about the visit to the respective Internet pages, which are stored on the user's computer in cookies, among other things. These text files are read out for specific product recommendations during subsequent visits to the website. For this purpose, a randomly generated identification number is stored in the cookies. Neither this number nor the information about your visits to the Internet pages can be assigned to you personally. Under no circumstances will this data be used to personally identify you as a visitor to our website.

**Affilinet**  
This website participates in partner programs of affilinet GmbH ("affilinet"), a service for integrating advertisements in the form of text links, image links, advertising banners or input masks. Affilinet uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. Affilinet also uses so-called web beacons (invisible graphics). These web beacons can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on these pages. The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of this website (including your IP address) and delivery of advertising formats is transferred to an affilinet server and stored there. affilinet may pass this information on to affilinet's contractual partners. However, Affilinet will not merge your IP address with other data stored by you. Further information on data use can be found in affilinet's data protection declaration: <https://www.affili.net/de/footeritem/datenschutz>

**Awin**  
This website uses the Performance Advertising Network of AWIN AG, Eichhornstraße 3, 10785 Berlin. Within the scope of its tracking services, AWIN stores cookies to document transactions (e.g. leads and sales) on end devices of users who visit or use websites or other online offers of its customers (e.g. register for a newsletter or place an order in an online shop). These cookies serve only the purpose of correctly allocating the success of an advertising medium and the corresponding billing within its network. AWIN does not collect, process or use personal data. A cookie only contains information about when a particular advertising medium was clicked on by a terminal device. The AWIN Tracking Cookies contain an individual sequence of digits which cannot be assigned to the individual user and which documents the affiliate program of an advertiser, the publisher, the time of the user's action (click or view). AWIN also collects information about the mobile device from which a transaction is executed, e.g. the operating system and the calling browser. For more information on AWIN's data processing, please visit: <https://www.awin.com/de/rechtliches/privacy-policy>

**Google AdWords**  
This website uses tools for "online marketing" from Google Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. This serves to recognize that a visitor has come across our website via a Google ad. Google uses cookies which are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of the use of the website. The cookies for the so-called "conversion tracking" are set when you click on an ad placed by Google. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you wish to prevent "conversion tracking", you can set your browser to block cookies from the "googleadservices.com" domain. You can also exercise your right to opt-out. If you would like to learn more about these methods or to know what options you have to prevent this information from being used by Google, click here: <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated>

**Adobe Media Optimizer**  
Our website uses Adobe Media Optimizer, a bid management service from Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited, 4-6 Riverwalk, Citywest Business Campus, Dublin 24, Republic of Ireland. Among other things, Adobe Media Optimizer uses cookies that are stored on your computer to help analyze your use of the website. In the context of use, data, such as in particular the IP address and activities of users, may be transmitted to and stored on a server of Adobe Systems GmbH. Adobe Systems GmbH may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where such data is processed by third parties.

**Facebook Custom Audience Pixel**  
We use "Custom Audiences Pixel" from Facebook Inc, 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook") to present interest-based advertisements to visitors to our website during their visit to Facebook. We have implemented a pixel from Facebook on our website, which establishes a direct connection to the Facebook servers when you visit our website. This information is transmitted to the Facebook server that you have visited our website and Facebook assigns this information to your personal Facebook user account. For more information about Facebook's collection and use of the data and your rights and choices about protecting your privacy, please see Facebook's privacy policy at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. If you would like to object to the described connection with Facebook, you can do so by clicking on this link.

**Bazaarvoice**  
To improve customer satisfaction, we work with Bazaarvoice, a US software manufacturer headquartered in Austin, Texas, and offices around the world. Bazaarvoice helps brands and retailers reach out to buyers and win them as customers through trusted, consumer-generated content. Bazaarvoice distributes, moderates and checks user-generated content - from ratings & reviews, visual content such as photos and videos to the'question-answer feature'. Cookies or similar technologies are used to collect information about consumers on the Bazaarvoice network to find out how users interact with this content. Bazaarvoice uses its own cookies and third party cookies in the Bazaarvoice network. Bazaarvoice uses cookies to merge your data across different websites. These technologies may collect the IP address of your computer, the pages you visit within the Bazaarvoice network, the date and time of your visits, browser type and version, and other clickstream data (collectively, "analytics and tracking data"). You can change the settings for the use of cookies individually in your browser, but blocking the use of cookies can restrict your use of certain functions of a website or service.

**Social Plugins / Links to Social Media Operators**  
Our websites use social plugins from the following social networks (hereinafter referred to as "social networks"):   
Facebook (operated by: Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA) Google Plus (Operator: Google Inc., 16+00 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA)

**Enable social plugins**  
In the interest of the most comprehensive protection of your data, Conrad uses technical solutions that ensure that data transfer via social plugins to the respective operator of the social network does not take place without prior activation of the social plugins by you. 

Social plugins that are deactivated in their initial status are integrated on our websites and do not establish contact with Facebook servers or other operators of social networks without appropriate activation. If you activate these deactivated plug-ins by clicking on the "Activate Social Media" button at the end of a website, you thereby declare your consent to the transmission of the data described in Section 3.2 below to the social networks. After activation, the social plugins establish a connection to the respective social network. With a further click you can then send a recommendation within the respective social network. If you are already logged in to a social network while you are visiting our websites, no further login dialog may be displayed. 

Clicking on the "Activate Social Media" button therefore means that you give your consent for the data described in Section 3.2 below to be transmitted to the respective operator of the social network. 

However, this only applies to the website just opened and the specifically selected social media operator. The consent is valid for one session and must be renewed each time you leave our website after each subsequent visit. 

The consent can be cancelled at any time by clicking on the "Deactivate Social Media" button. 

In addition to the social plugins, our websites also contain simple links to Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest, del.icio.us, Mister Wong, LinkedIn, MySpace. 

Data exchange with the social media operators mentioned only takes place when the corresponding icon button (e.g. the "f" of Facebook, the bird symbol of Twitter, the "+1" symbol of Google Plus) is clicked. If you click on such an icon button, a page of the corresponding social media operator opens in a popup window. There you can publish information about our products according to the regulations of the social media operator.

**Data transfer via social plugins**  
If you activate the social plugins that are deactivated by default (cf. Section 3.1), a connection is established with the social network servers. Each social plugin then transmits data to the respective social network. We have no influence on the amount of data that the respective social network collects with the help of the social plugin. As far as we know, social networks receive information about which of our websites you have visited currently and previously. With each activated social plugin, a cookie with a unique identifier is set each time the relevant website is called. This enables the social network to create a profile of your usage behavior. It cannot be ruled out that such a profile can be assigned to you even if you register with the social network for the first time at a later date. 

If you are already logged in to a social network when you visit our websites, the operator of this social network may be able to assign the visit to your personal account as soon as you activate the social plug-ins that are deactivated by default (see Section 3.1). When using social plugin functions (e.g. "I like" button, making a comment), the information is transmitted directly from your browser to the corresponding social network and stored there. The same applies when calling up a website of a social media operator by clicking on the corresponding icon button. 

If you are not a member of a social network, the social networks may still receive and store your IP address and information about the browser and operating system you are using after you activate the social plugins. For the scope and purpose of the collection, processing and use of the data by social networks and information on rights and privacy preferences, please refer to the privacy policy of the respective social network. 

If you are a member of a social network and wish to limit the collection of data through our websites and the merging of your user data with the data stored about you on the social network, you should log out of the social network before visiting our websites. 

We encourage you to use appropriate add-ons for the browser you are using (e.g. "Facebook Blocker"). However, we cannot guarantee the effectiveness of such solutions.

**Consent to abuse prevention and detection measures**  
This website uses technologies from infoscore Consumer Data GmbH, Rheinstraße 99, 76532 Baden-Baden, Germany, to collect, store and use the data of the devices you use when visiting the website for the purpose of preventing and identifying misuse. 

With your purchase, you agree that your data for contract processing (e.g. object of purchase, name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, date of birth, delivery address, method of payment and bank data) will be transmitted by CONRAD to infoscore Consumer Data GmbH, Rheinstraße 99, 76532 Baden-Baden, for the purpose of preventing and identifying misuse, and that data together with a cookie and/or a visitor ID, which may contain data of your terminal devices used when visiting the website and via which your terminal devices used can be recognised with a certain probability during further visits, are collected, processed and used by infoscore Consumer Data GmbH, Rheinstraße 99, 76532 Baden-Baden with the purpose of automatically checking whether there are any indications of misuse of the website. CONRAD has commissioned infoscore Consumer Data GmbH, Rheinstraße 99, 76532 Baden-Baden as contract data processor in accordance with § 11 BDSG to carry out the risk assessment and prevent and identify misuse. You affirm that you may give your consent to all end devices used by you when visiting our online shop. 

You can object to the collection, storage and use of data at any time with effect for the future with regard to the terminals used by you for visiting this online shop via the following link: <http://www.infoscore-tracking-technology.de/optout/form/72769>. The data of the terminals used will then be deleted despite any consent given. is also no longer used for the purpose of preventing and detecting abuse. The use of this online shop may be restricted as a result.

**Push notifications**  
If push messages are enabled, the Apple Push Notification Service (iOS version) or Google Cloud Messaging (Android version) is used to deliver this feature. For the delivery of push messages it is necessary to transfer non-personal data (e.g. product names) to these services. To enable secure communication with the user's mobile device, a device token must be exchanged. This is the only way to identify the user's device when sending the push message.

**Location information**  
For certain functions, we may need access to the location of your device. In such a case, we collect your current location via GPS so that we can quickly provide you with information about your immediate surroundings. Data about your location will only be used to process your request. Your location data is transmitted via an encrypted connection, e.g. to locate the nearest branch, whereby the data is anonymised after completion of your request and statistically evaluated to improve our service.

**Application process - General information**  
We attach particular importance to the protection of your personal data and compliance with the data protection guidelines. We will not sell or pass on your personal data to third parties. This electronic application page is also operated by Conrad Electronic SE Germany for other companies of the Conrad Group.   
Any personal data, including any personal data contained in the attachments (hereinafter referred to as "data"), which you make available to us via this applicant page, will be collected, processed and used by Conrad for the purpose of processing your application. The provisions of the EU Data Protection Directive 95/46 and all other relevant data protection laws are fully complied with.   
To enable your data (your candidate profile) to be taken into account outside of a current job posting, the following visibility options are offered to you:   
Please note that visibility option 2 (see below) is preselected.   
Your data will only be used to fill the vacancies for which you have applied. They are not passed on within the Conrad Group. Your data will be passed on to companies of the Conrad Group within your country of residence to fill vacancies. Your data will be passed on within the Conrad Group worldwide to fill vacancies.

**Data retention**  
Your data is stored in encrypted form in a computer centre in the European Union or the European Economic Area.   
Your data is protected against unauthorized access by encrypted transmission, encrypted storage, a role and authorization concept, a data backup concept and physical security measures for the servers.

**Access to data**  
The people within the Conrad Group required to fill vacancies have access to your stored data depending on the option you have selected (1-3).   
To ensure proper operation, selected employees of the Conrad Group have access to your data as well as selected employees of external service companies who support Conrad in the automated processing of the data.

**Data retrieval, maintenance and deletion; right of objection**  
You can view your data at any time via the application. In addition, you have the right at any time to have any data blocked or deleted, to object to the processing of the data or to have incorrect data corrected If you do not arrange for your data to be deleted, it will remain stored for up to twelve (12) months after completion of the application process in order to open up further career opportunities with Conrad. This period applies to all your applications and starts again with each registration.

**Data protection officer**  
If you believe that we are not adhering to the provisions of this statement or if you have any questions about data protection, please contact our data protection officer: 

Conrad Electronic SE  
Data Protection Officer  
Klaus Conrad St. 1  
92240 Hirschau

E-mail: [datenschutz@conrad.de](mailto:datenschutz@conrad.de)

**Declaration of consent under data protection law**  
To continue the application process, please agree to the following points. You can revoke this declaration of consent under data protection law at any time by sending an e-mail to personalmanagement@conrad.de   
I agree to the collection, processing and use of my personal data as described in the "Information on the application process". If I provide special types of personal data in my application (e.g. also through information in the attachments attached by me), I hereby expressly agree that this data will be treated in the same way as described in the "Information on the application process".

**Newsletter**  
Our newsletter is analyzed with technologies from Agnitas, Google and Exactag on click rates, time of the call, etc.. For more detailed information on these tools, please refer to this Privacy Policy above. To object to the use of these technologies, you have the option of clicking on a personal "Do Not Track" link in each e-mail. If you do this, the "Agnitas" system will store that you as the recipient with this e-mail address will not store any usage data in the future.   
To object to the use of Exactag regarding website usage, call and click measurement, please use the following opt-out link.   
The procedure is the same as unsubscribing newsletters, but with the difference that you as the recipient will remain on the mailing list, but your usage behaviour will no longer be measured in the future. Please note that another objection is necessary if you delete your cookies.

**You have questions about data protection...we are here for you  
Your right to information**  
According to the GDPR, you have a right to information.  
Who is responsible for data processing and to whom can you contact?  
Responsible is Conrad Electronic SE, Klaus-Conrad-Str. 1, 92240 Hirschau, Germany, e-mail: datenschutz@conrad.de, fax: +49 180 5 312110 (0.14 €/min. incl. VAT from the fixed network)

The data protection officer at Conrad is

Christian Volkmer  
Project 29 GmbH & Co. KG  
Ostengasse 14  
93047 Regensburg   
Germany

E-mail: [datenschutz@conrad.de](mailto:datenschutz@conrad.de)

Phone: +49 941 2986930

**Which data are processed and from which sources?**  
We process the data that we have received from you within the framework of the purchase contract or transaction, on the basis of consents or within the framework of your application to us or within the framework of your staff.

**Personal data includes:**  
Your master/contact data, this includes, for buyers, e.g. first and last name, address, contact data (e-mail address, telephone number, fax), date of birth, bank or payment data.   
For applicants and employees this includes, for example, first and last name, address, contact data (e-mail address, telephone number, fax), date of birth, data from CV and references, bank data, religious affiliation.   
In the case of suppliers, this includes, for example, the name of their legal representatives, company, trade register number, VAT ID number, company number, address, contact person contact data (e-mail address, telephone number, fax), bank data.   
In addition, we also process the following other personal data:   
Information on the type and content of contract data, order data, sales and document data, customer and supplier history and consulting documents, Advertising and sales data, Information from your electronic traffic with CONRAD (e.g. IP address, log-in data), other data that we have received from you in the course of our business relationship (e.g. in customer meetings), Data that we generate ourselves from master / contact data and other data, e.g. by means of customer requirements and customer potential analyses, the documentation of your declaration of consent for the receipt of e.g. newsletters.

**For what purposes and on what legal basis will the data be processed?**  
We process your data in accordance with the provisions of the Basic Data Protection Ordinance (DS-GVO) and the Federal Data Protection Act 2018 in the currently valid version: 

for the fulfilment of (pre-)contractual obligations (Art 6 Para. 1lit.b DS-GMO): Your data will be used to process your purchases online or in one of our branches or to process the contracts of your employees in our company. The data will be processed in particular during the initiation of business transactions and the execution of contracts with you. 

to fulfil legal obligations (Art 6 Para. 1 lit.c DS-GMO): A processing of your data is necessary for the purpose of fulfilling different legal obligations, e.g. from the Commercial Code or the Tax Code. 

to protect legitimate interests (Art 6 Para. 1 lit.f DS-GMO): On the basis of a balance of interests, data may be processed beyond the actual performance of the contract to protect the legitimate interests of us or third parties. Data processing to protect legitimate interests takes place in the following cases, for example: Advertising or marketing (see No. 4), Measures for business management and further development of services and products; Maintaining a group-wide customer database to improve customer service in the context of legal proceedings. 

within the scope of your consent (Art 6 Para. 1lit.a DSGVO): If you have given us your consent to the processing of your data, e.g. to the delivery of our newsletter, processing will only take place in accordance with the purposes and to the extent agreed in the declaration of consent. A given consent can be revoked at any time with effect for the future.

**Processing of personal data for advertising purposes**  
You can object to the use of your personal data for advertising purposes at any time, either as a whole or for individual measures, without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs according to the basic rates.   
CONRAD is entitled under the local legal requirements of to use the e-mail address you provided when concluding the contract for direct advertising for its own similar goods or services. You will receive these product recommendations from us regardless of whether you have subscribed to a newsletter.   
If you do not wish to receive such recommendations from us by e-mail, you can object to the use of your address for this purpose at any time without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs according to the basic rates. A message in text form is sufficient for this. Of course, every e-mail always contains a unsubscribe link.

**Who receives my data?**  
If we use a service provider in the sense of order processing, we nevertheless remain responsible for the protection of your data. All contractors are contractually obliged to treat your data confidentially and to process it only within the scope of the provision of services. The contractors commissioned by us will receive your data if they require it to perform their respective services. These are, for example, IT service providers that we need for the operation and security of our IT system as well as advertising and address publishers for our own advertising campaigns.   
Your data will be processed in the CONRAD customer database. The CONRAD customer database supports the enhancement of the data quality of existing customer data (duplicate cleanup, moved/dead indicator, address correction), and enables enrichment with data from public sources.   
This data is made available to the group companies CONRADS to the extent necessary to process the contract. The storage of customer data is company-related and separate, with CONRAD acting as a service provider for the individual participating companies.   
If there is a legal obligation and in the context of legal prosecution, authorities and courts as well as external auditors may be recipients of your data.   
In addition, insurance companies, banks, credit agencies and service providers may also be recipients of your data for the purpose of initiating and fulfilling contracts.

**How long will my data be stored?**  
We process your data until the end of the business relationship or until the expiry of the applicable statutory retention periods; in addition, until the end of any legal disputes in which the data is required as evidence. 

**Is personal data transferred to a third country?**  
In principle, we do not transfer any data to a third country. A transmission will only take place in individual cases on the basis of an adequacy decision of the European Commission, standard contractual clauses, suitable guarantees or your express consent.

**What data protection rights do I have?**  
You have a right to information, correction, deletion or restriction of the processing of your stored data, a right of objection against the processing as well as a right to data transferability and to a complaint in accordance with the requirements of data protection law. 

**Right to information:**  
You can request information from us as to whether and to what extent we process your data.

**Right to correction:**  
If we process your data that is incomplete or incorrect, you can request that we correct or complete it at any time.

**Right of deletion:**  
You can request us to delete your data if we process it unlawfully or if the processing interferes disproportionately with your legitimate protection interests. Please note that there may be reasons that prevent immediate deletion, e.g. in the case of legally regulated storage obligations.   
Irrespective of the exercise of your right to deletion, we will delete your data immediately and completely, unless there is a legal transaction or legal obligation to retain it.

**Right to limitation of processing:**  
You may request us to restrict the processing of your data if you dispute the accuracy of the data for a period of time that allows us to verify the accuracy of the data. the processing of the data is unlawful, but you refuse to delete it and instead request a restriction on the use of the data, we no longer need the data for the intended purpose, but you still need this data to assert or defend legal claims, or you have lodged an objection to the processing of the data.

**Right to data transferability:**  
You may require us to provide you with the data you have provided to us in a structured, current and machine-readable format and to allow you to pass this data to another person in charge without our interference, provided that we process this data on the basis of an agreement you have given and revocable or to fulfil a contract between us, and this processing is carried out using automated methods. If it is technically feasible, you can ask us to transfer your data directly to another person responsible.

**Right of objection:**  
If we process your data for legitimate reasons, you can object to this data processing at any time; this would also apply to profiling based on these provisions. We will then no longer process your data unless we can prove compelling reasons worthy of protection for the processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. You can object to the processing of your data for the purpose of direct advertising at any time without giving reasons.

**Right of appeal:**  
If you are of the opinion that we violate German or European data protection law when processing your data, please contact us to clarify any questions. Of course, you also have the right to contact the supervisory authority responsible for you, the respective state office for data protection supervision.   
If you wish to assert any of the above rights against us, please contact our data protection officer. In case of doubt, we may request additional information to confirm your identity.

**Am I obliged to provide data?**  
The processing of your data is necessary to conclude or fulfil your contract with us. If you do not provide us with this information, we will usually have to refuse to enter into the contract or will no longer be able to execute an existing contract and will therefore have to terminate it. However, you are not obliged to give your consent to the processing of data that is not relevant or legally required for the fulfilment of the contract.

**Enquiries, Requests and Notifications**  
If you have any questions about the protection of your personal information at Conrad or would like to request the personal data we hold about you to be disclosed to you, amended or deleted, please write to Conrad Electronic International GmbH & Co KG, Durisolstrasse 2, 4600 Wels, Austria, or email us at [sales@conrad.com](mailto:sales@conrad.com).

Effective from May 25, 2018
